# Akshay **Kalyan**



40 Butler Stoney Crescent, Auckland 0992, New Zealand



akshaykalyan@outlook.com



+64 27 727 6866



# Objective

Software Engineer in Development

# Profile

Currently I am an undergraduate student at the University of Auckland, undertaking a Bachelor of Engineering specialising in Software Engineering. My passion in technology has placed me in the position I am in today, pursuing the rapidly growing field of Computer Science and Software. I look forward to contributing to the industry and aid in the evolution of our day to day life.

# **Education**

# Bachelor of Engineering (Honors), Software Engineering The University of Auckland 2012 – 2016 [expected]

CGPA: 8.7 / 9.0.

# National Certificate of Educational Achievement (NCEA)

2009 – 2011

Otumoetai College Level 3 with Excellence.

# Awards and Certificates

### Dean's Honours List

2013

University of Auckland

Awarded to the top 5% of Software Engineering students in the academic year.

### Dean's Honours List

2012

University of Auckland

Awarded to the top 5% of Engineering students in the academic year.

### First in Course Award

University of Auckland

ENGGEN 131: Introduction to Engineering Computation and Software Development.

# Recent Projects

### Pebble Watchface: Trace

Personal Project

 $\label{thm:constraint} \mbox{Technologies: C Language, Javascript, jQuery Mobile, Pebble SDK 2.0.}$ 

- Designed and created a minimalist watchface for the Pebble smartwatch, deployed via the Appstore.
- Over 1,000 unique users of the application to date.

# Android Application: Contacts Now

University Project - Individual

Technologies: Java, SQLite, Android SDK.

- Designed and constructed a contact management application from scratch over a 6 week period.
- Implemented direct manipulation of contact data to call, send SMS, get directions and more.

# **Employment**

# Sapphire Solutions Limited

Dec 2013 - Feb 2014

Intern

- Redesigned, constructed, and deployed the company's website using modern HTML5 and CSS3 standards.
- Incorporated Search Engine Optimisation (SEO) techniques to increase web presence.
- Created software tools in C# for internal and external use to assist the operations of the business.
- Prepared client computers for off-site installation.

# **Target Road Tyres**

Jan 2012 – Feb 2013

Administrator / Developer

- Involved in creating a 10 page website to allow the company to showcase thier products and services.
- Implemented standard Search Engine Optimisation (SEO) techniques.
- Tasked with administrative responsibilities including managing stock and providing tailored solutions for customers.

# Volunteer Work

# Peer Support Programme

2011

Student Mentor

- Participated in one-on-one interaction with a group of first year college students to provide mentorship.
- Helped peers adjust to college life by listening to and rectifying any academic or social issues they were experiencing.

# Skills

# Languages

Java C#

C++

C

Python

# Internet Technologies

HTML5 & CSS3 Javascript

### Mobile Development

Android

### Design

Adobe Illustrator Adobe Fireworks Adobe Photoshop

# **Operating Systems**

Windows XP, 7, 8 Mac OS X 10.7

Linux

# Academic Transcript

Available on Request